《朝圣之路》前情提要
Previously on "The Path"...
最好和最后的
Best and final.
你指控史蒂文·迈耶骚扰你
You're accusing Steven Meyer of molesting you.
-是的  -你想要什么
‐ Yeah. ‐ What do you want?
我想要做领导者  为运动代言
I want to be out in front, speaking for The Movement.
你为什么见他
Why are you meeting with him?
你希望从中得到什么
What are you hoping to gain from this?
除非我听完他的话  不然他就一直跟着我
He won't stop following me until I hear him out.
我每天都在为你祈祷
I am praying for you every day.
我们不需要你那该死的祈祷
I don't need your fucking prayers.
我把尿布袋落在饭桌上了
I left the diaper bag in the diner.
-我爸爸拿走了  -我们会买新的的
- And my dad took it. ‐ We'll get a new one.
穆萨带走了所有东西
Musa's moved all their stuff out.
这可能和你没什么关系
It probably has nothing to do with you.
那他为什么不回我的信息
Then why isn't he answering any of my texts?
-我不知道  -他完全没有
‐ I don't know. ‐ Well, he hasn't
帮助过你  是吧
reached out to you at all, has he?
我相信你
I believe in you.
我只是光明的魂器
You know, I'm just a vessel for The Light.
你可不像光明的魂器
You don't feel like just a vessel for The Light.
我昨晚吃了药
I took the medicine last night.
我在路上  而你在另一条路
I was on one path, and you were on a different one.
你不会迷路  但你也不会再回来了
You weren't lost, but you weren't coming back.
朝圣之路  第三季  第六集
因为被水打湿了
Okay, so, the water damage
这上面很多东西都有点难以辨认
made a lot of this indecipherable,
但我觉得我肯定能弄明白
but I think that I finally figured out...
这可能是什么
what this could possibly be.
我觉得我们面前的是
And I think that we are looking at the very first draft
阶梯的最初草稿
of The Ladder.
我认为还有一位第二作者
And I believe that there's a second author.
-什么  -在这里
‐ What? ‐ Um, so right here,
光明并没有被描述成一种正面力量
The Light is not described as a benevolent force,
而是"用火来清洁并烧尽"
but, "A fire that cleanses and burns."
那个女人
The woman...
视频里的  利莉思
from the video, Lilith.
有可能  看这个
Well, possibly. Look at this.
萨拉  这笔迹都不一样
I mean, Sarah, even the handwriting is different.
不对  如果她帮他写了这个
No, but if she helped him write this...
那对别人就不管用了
It doesn't work with someone else.
-什么  -故事
‐ What? ‐ The story.
我知道你觉得很荒谬
Look, I know you think it's ridiculous
史蒂文·迈耶博士爬上火梯
that Dr. Steven Meyer climbed a ladder of fire
上到高层  但是
and received the rungs, but‐‐
没有什么比离开红海
It's no more ridiculous than parting the Red Sea
和把水变酒更荒谬的了[圣经典故]
or turning water into wine.
每一个伟大的信仰都需要神话基础
They're the foundational myths of every great faith.
这不该只是神话
It's not supposed to be a myth.
我一生中从未质疑过真相
You know, never once in my life did I ever question truth.
如果光明并不存在  那会有什么
If there's no Light, then what else is there?
这依然存疑  萨拉
There's doubt, Sarah...
对死亡的恐惧
and fear of death.
还有
And there is
迫切的
this urgent...
生的需求
immediacy to life.
听我说
Listen to me.
你还有没体验过的生活
There's a life you haven't lived yet...
比如寿司  比如大学
with sushi and college.
-太晚了  -真的吗
‐ It's too late for that. ‐ Is it?
萨拉  我知道现在是很痛苦的时候
Sarah, I know this is painful right now...
但彼岸有那么多奇迹
But there's so much that's miraculous on the other side.
这对你来说不只是研究
This wasn't just research for you.
你说什么
Sorry?
你是因为我才研究的
You did this for me.
我是因为自己喜欢才做的
It's work I love.
没错  我的确想让你知道你自己发现了什么
Yes. I wanted you to know what you'd found.
如果这让你不舒服了  我很抱歉  我明...
I'm sorry if this makes you uncomfortable. I underst‐‐
今天我选择在"光明"中绽放光芒
第一周工作感觉如何
How's your first week of work?
很开心能坐在桌子的这一边
It's nice to be on this side of the desk.
如果你有什么需要尽管提
Well, let us know if there's anything you need.
今天我选择在"光明"中绽放光芒
大厅那边有人等着
Oh, and there's someone here in the lobby.
-你有空接待一下吗  -当然
- Do you have time for a walk‐in? ‐ Sure.
今天我选择在"光明"中绽放光芒
你好啊  玛丽
Hello, Mary.
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
你看起来不是很想见到我
You don't look happy to see me.
首席翻译官
█ 网易见外
上次我见到你的时候  你把我脑袋摁水底下来着
Last time I saw you, you held my head underwater.
没错  你走的时候很生气
That's right. You were angry when you left.
首席校对官
人人译视界
·
人人
-是吧  -你在这干嘛
- Weren't you? ‐ What are you doing here?
我是来求助的  这是你的工作  对吧
I'm here for help. That's your job, isn't it?
翻译     一只虾   刁萌
你帮助吸毒的人
You help people with drug problems.
-哈罗德  -我一天吃20片止疼片
‐ Harold  ‐ I take 20 painkillers a day,
翻译     Ievo
但还是一下床就疼
and still it hurts just to get out of bed.
翻译     L   Jevoudrais
我的身体破碎了  玛丽
My body is broken, Mary,
校对     小酸奶
可我有的只是几个微不足道的戒指
and all I've got to show for it is a couple of measly rings.
-听我说  -当然
‐ Listen to me‐‐ ‐ Granted, they're worth
它们每个价值五万
50,000 each,
时间轴     姜姜   魚鱼鱼
但这些戒指花掉了我所有的钱
but those rings cost me everything.
我经常注意到小索尔在看着它们
And I always noticed Small Saul looking at them...
后期     8T
觊觎它们
coveting them.
总监     小酸奶
-小索尔  -是的
‐ Small Saul? ‐ Yeah.
如果有人拿了戒指  那一定是他
I mean, if anyone took those rings, it was him.
┌
┐
└
┘
人人影视官方客户端
唯一下载渠道
app.YYeTs.com
┌
┐
└
┘
什么
What?
我没提到它们丢了啊
I didn't say they were missing.
逮到你了
I got you.
-怎么了  -很抱歉
‐ What's wrong? ‐ I'm so sorry.
-哈罗德  怎么  -不
‐ Harold. What‐‐Hey‐ ‐ No, no.
等下  等下
Hold on. Ho‐‐ho‐‐ho‐‐oh‐‐
很高兴见到你
It's so good to see you.
-还有森林  -好啊
‐ And Forest too. ‐ Yeah.
你到底来这干嘛
Wait, no. Hey, what the hell are you doing here?
我偷了他的戒指  然后
I stole his rings, and then, um, I‐‐
我卖掉了  但是我把钱弄丢了
I sold them, but I lost the money.
什么
Wait, what‐‐what?
我把钱放在尿布袋里了
I left them in the diaper bag.
-我爸爸拿走了  -等下  什么
- My dad took them. ‐ Sorry, what‐‐what are you‐‐
我在追踪我爸爸  我会把钱拿回来
But I'm tracking my dad. I'm gonna get the money back.
等等  玛丽  你到底干了些什么
Wait, Mary, what the hell have you done?
等等
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
我不在意钱  玛丽
I don't care about the money, Mary.
我们俩要一起去寻宝了
You and I are going on a treasure hunt.
没错
Yes, we are.
是的  我们一起  你爸爸和我
Yes, we are. Me and Daddy.
我觉得秘鲁能改变人
I see Peru was transformative.
你走时是位园丁  回来之后成了工匠
You left a gardener and came back a handyman.
你要知道  我可建了校园里的第一所宿舍
I'll have you know, I built the very first dorm on campus.
是的  我知道了
Uh, yeah. No, I know.
就是塌了的那个  对吧
That's the one that collapsed, right?
保持了八个月
Lasted eight months.
我只是觉得夏天会喜欢树屋
I just thought Summer would enjoy a tree house.
我成长过程中有过一个  不过
I had one growing up, and, uh‐‐
她可能有点大了  不一定适合
Eh, maybe she's too old for it.
我就是有点抱歉错过了她的演出
I just feel bad about missing her in her play.
她会喜欢的
She's gonna love it.
你需要帮助吗
You, uh, you want some help?
我以为光明守护者
I think the Guardian of the Light
会有更紧迫的事要做
has more pressing matters.
不是
Uh, no.
什么
What?
我们已经在法国开了中心了吗
Are we really opening a center in France?
是的  我过几天就过去做圣事
Yeah. I'm leaving in a couple days to consecrate it myself.
那可有很多事要做  埃迪
This is huge, Eddie.
我在想  我可能需要有人
You know, I was thinking that I'm gonna need someone
过去帮忙几个月
to go out there in a few months,
看看进度之类的
you know, check on the progress.
你和加布有兴趣吗
You and Gaby up for the job?
你应该往下一点
You know, you should grip further down.
-什么  -我是说锤子
‐ What? ‐ On the hammer.
你像这样握着它
You're holding it like this.
往下一点  你就能获得更多力量
A little further down, you get more leverage.
看出来区别了吗
See? Hear the difference?
你有你的办法  我有我的
Well, you have your method, I have mine.
也是
Fair enough.
法国的事先别告诉加布
Hey, don't tell Gaby about France.
-我要给他一个惊喜  -没问题
- I want it to be a surprise. ‐ You got it.
这就累了吗
Taking a break already, huh?
汉克
Hank.
喂
Hey!
喂  喂喂喂  我操  醒醒
Hey. Hey, hey. Hey. Oh, shit. Hey. Hey.
来人啊
Help!
快打电话
Call someone.
醒醒  汉克  醒醒  汉克
Hey, Hank. Hey, Hank.
汉克  醒醒
Hank. Hey.
我还从没和异教徒在一起过
I've never been with a heathen before.
你感觉自己堕落了吗
Do you feel corrupted?
我感觉...很好
I feel... good.
你听见什么声音了没
Do you hear something?
什么
What?
我看下
Let me check.
别
Stop.
埃迪  未接来电  加布  未接来电  特莎  未接来电
如果你可以联系法国的基地
If you could call the outpost in France...
嗯  我已经通知他们我们得延期了
Yeah, I've already let them know we need to postpone.
天啊  我本来今晚应该主持一场研讨会的
God, I was supposed to teach a workshop tonight.
所有研讨会都取消了
All classes have been canceled.
事实上  我已经取消了你剩下这周
In fact, I've cleared your schedule
所有的日程安排  埃迪
for the rest of the week, Eddie.
你  你
You don't‐‐you‐‐
眼下你只要专注于这件事就好了
you don't need to focus on anything but this.
好吗
Okay?
我要进去了
I should head inside.
埃迪
Eddie.
我明白你现在得是组织的主心骨
I know you have to be a rock for the community right now,
但在我面前你不需要这样强撑
but you really don't need to be that way with me.
天啊
God.
如果你有什么需要
Well, if you need anything,
我一直都在
anytime, I'm‐‐I'm here.
好吗
Okay?
怎么了
What?
我只是
I'm just, uh‐‐
很幸运有你在我身边
just lucky to have you is all.
正如雪鸮保护着伊甸园
As the owl protects The Garden...
我们赐予汉克这双翅膀
we offer Hank these wings...
带他归家
to carry him home...
为他指引
To be his guide...
照看他
And to help watch‐‐
我  我来晚了吗
Did I‐‐did I miss it?
汉克在等你
Hank waited for you.
我没听见我...
I never heard my...
你来了  别的不重要
You're here now. That's all that matters here.
萨拉  我们本来准备开始祷告了
Sarah, we were about to start the blessing.
我希望能由你主导
I was hoping that you would lead it.
我们相信光明
We believe in The Light.
我们相信汉克·阿姆斯特朗
We believe Hank Armstrong
会在伊甸园里  活在光明中
will live his light in The Garden.
我们相信伊甸园
We believe in The Garden,
感谢史蒂文·迈耶登上阶梯
for all this was revealed to Steven Meyer
获知了《阶梯》  发现了伊甸园
as he ascended The Ladder and received the rungs.
请汉克摆脱这具凡胎
We now invite Hank to leave this earthly form behind,
因为在终结中
for in ending...
我们重生
We begin.
-痛苦中  -有喜悦
‐ And in sorrow... - We rejoice.
-黑暗中  -有光明
‐ And in darkness... - There is light.
你确定是这儿吗
Sure this is the place?
她给我的地址就是这儿
This is the address she gave us.
很高兴你没有参与这件事
I'm glad you weren't a part of this,
如果我老婆也把我蒙在鼓里
'cause if my lady had kept me in the dark,
像玛丽耍你那样耍我
played me the way Mary played you...
摇滚
等发令枪响吧
Wait for starter pistol.
尼娜
Nina.
我的不败战绩
Ah, still undefeated, eh?
下个谁
Ah. Who's next?
我
Me.
上个月你买了
Last month you bought
两枚冠军戒指
two championship rings.
听着  那两枚戒指对我朋友意义重大
Now, those rings are very valuable to my friend here.
如果我赢了
If I beat you...
戒指就还给我们
We get them back.
老子欣赏你
I like you.
但我只是个中间人
But I am middleman.
我已经把戒指给卖了
I sold the rings.
但我可以告诉你我卖给谁了
But I will tell you who I sold them to
前提是如果你朋友能打败我
if your friend can beat me.
-成交  -不  不行
‐ Deal. ‐ Hey, no. No deal.
不行  你得控制好自己
No deal. I need you to remain in control.
我来解决
I will handle this.
你是个商人
You're a businessman.
那行  我有个提议
Okay, so I'm gonna make you a proposition.
看见没
See?
你很弱
You are weak.
但你朋友体型真是完美
But your friend here is perfect physical specimen.
要是他赢了  我就给你们地址
If he wins, I will give you address.
要是我赢了
If I win...
我们就崩了你
We shoot you in the head.
过来
Come.
尼娜
Nina.
*花儿散落花瓣*
♪ Flowers cast off their petals ♪
*树木飘零树叶*
♪ And the trees shed all their leaves ♪
*天空烟雨濛濛*
♪ The sky began to weep with rain ♪
*但光明说  别忧伤*
♪ But The Light said, "Do not grieve." ♪
*此世之外还有个*
♪ There's a world beyond this world ♪
*充满温暖  爱情和歌曲的世界*
♪ With warmth and love and song ♪
*汉克已经来到了伊甸园*
♪ Hank is in The Garden now ♪
*那是他的归处*
♪ At home where he belongs ♪
真美  亲爱的
Oh, it's beautiful, sweetie.
真棒
That's great.
萨拉  你想说悼词吗
Sarah, you want to share your CO?
不了  现在就算了
Uh, not right now.
说吧  萨拉  该你了
Come on, Sarah. It's your turn.
-不用了  拉塞尔  -不  不行
‐ It's okay, Russel. ‐ No, no.
-轮到你了  -我说了不用了
- There's an order to this. ‐ I said no.
我有话要说
Uh, I can go,
如果  如果大家不介意的话
if‐‐if that's okay with everyone.
这下精彩了
This should be good.
不介意  当然不介意
Yeah, no. Of course.
他毕竟是你父亲
I mean, he was your father.
你不是迈耶教徒当然也能表示悼念
You don't have to be a Meyerist to share.
谢谢  能来到这儿对我来说真的意义重大
Thank you. I‐it means a lot for me to be here.
大家也都知道
Well, uh, a‐as most of you know,
我父亲  爸爸和我之前很久没说话了
um, my father‐‐Dad and I didn't speak for a long time.
所以当他最后来找到我
And, um, when he finally reached out to me
过了这么多年  我非常生气
after all those years, I was furious.
但我也很高兴  因为撇开信仰的事
But I was also so happy, because faith or no faith,
我还是  我很爱爸爸
I still‐‐I loved Dad so much.
所以我同意见他
So I‐I agreed to meet him,
条件是见面地点必须在赛马场
but only if we did it at the racetrack.
在那之前我从来没赌过马
And, um, I never bet on horses before,
我只是想借此惩罚他  所以挑了个
but I was just trying to punish him by picking a place
迈耶教徒肯定会讨厌的地方
that I knew Meyerists would hate.
结果  最后那天我们过得很愉快
And the thing is, we ended up having the best day.
几周后  有一天我问他
And then a few weeks later when I asked him
他想去哪儿  他说赛马场
where he wanted to go, he said the track.
-后来每个月  -故事很美好  特莎
- And month after month‐‐ ‐ That's a great story, Tessa.
-下一个谁来讲  -她还没说完呢
- Uh, who'd like to go next? ‐ She's not finished yet.
我们是来颂扬爸爸作为迈耶教徒的一生
We're here to celebrate Dad's life as a Meyerist,
而不是披露他违反教规的次数
not talk about the times he broke the rules.
-大家能别吵了吗  -她很伤心
‐ Can we not argue right now? ‐ She's grieving.
听着  霍克说的没错  好吗
Look, Hawk is right, okay?
特莎  你说吧
Tessa, please.
我刚担心的就是这样
That's what I was worried about.
你有什么想说的吗  妮可
Do you have something you want to say, Nicole?
对一个没有接电话
For someone who didn't pick up her phone
都不接电话的人来说  你可真有脸
as her father was dying, you have a lot of nerve--
-好了  够了  -够了
- Okay, that is enough. - Screw this.
霍克  亲爱的
Hawk, sweetie--
是啊  萨拉
Yeah, Sarah...
你当时在哪呢
Where were you?
她当时在哪和你无关  拉塞尔
It's none of your business where she was, Russel.
-特莎  你可以离开了  -去你的  拉塞尔
- Tessa, you can leave. - Fuck you, Russel.
他是她的父亲
He was her father.
如果这让你感到不舒服  我道歉
And I'm sorry if that was inconvenient for you.
我很抱歉  抱歉特莎居然敢
I'm sorry that--that Tessa had the audacity
问问题
to ask questions.
我知道你只想坐在这里
You know, I know that you just want to sit there
弹你的好听的小曲
and play your cute little songs.
但是我们健健康康的父亲
But our perfectly healthy father
刚刚死于心脏病
just died of a heart attack,
我很抱歉我没有庆祝演出
and I'm sorry I don't have a celebratory offering.
-我很生气  -那你走吧
- I am pissed off. - Then leave.
-加比  -不  这不是好听的歌
- Gaby. - No, these aren't cute songs
和为了让我们自己感觉好而编的故事
and stories we tell to make ourselves feel better.
这是我们神圣的仪式和传统
These are our sacred rites and traditions.
我要感谢他们每一个人
And I plan to honor every one of them.
你们的父亲是迈耶教徒
Your father was a Meyerist.
-我们知道  妈妈  -不  我认为你们不知道
- We know that, Mom. - No, I don't think you do.
汉克全心全意地爱着你
Hank loved you with all his heart.
但是你不信教让他每天都心碎极了
But your lack of faith shattered him every day.
汉克和我一直向彼此
Hank and I made an oath to each other
以及这场运动发誓
and to this Movement for all time.
任何人对他的信仰不敬
And anyone who disrespects his faith
都是在侮辱他的回忆
desecrates his memory.
懂了吗
Is that understood?
很好
Good.
谁是下一个
Who's next?
霍克
Hey, Hawk.
乔伊把你祖父的事发给我了
Uh, Joy sent me a text about your grandfather.
该死的  乔伊
Damn it, Joy.
天哪  我不敢相信她用他的死来引诱你
God, I cannot believe she would use his death to lure you.
不不不  听着  应该道歉的人是我
No, no, no, look, I should be the one apologizing.
我  我让她上去
I-I led her on
然后消失掉的
and completely disappeared.
我  我对此很抱歉
I'm--I'm sorry about that.
我们不穿深颜色的衣服
We don't wear dark colors.
这的确是我们唯一不穿的东西
It's literally the only thing we don't wear.
我真的不是  要说什么
I honestly didn't, like, mean anything by that.
-我只是想  -不不
- I just figured, you know... - No, no, um--
我很抱歉  你  你
I'm sorry. Uh, you--you look--
你还好吗
How are you holding up?
没事的
It's okay.
这就像  那  那里发生了什么
It's just like, what--what's going on in there...
天哪  这是我祖父
God, man, it's the last thing
期望的最后一件事
my grandfather would've wanted.
他不在乎我们
I mean, he didn't care if...
我们生气还是开心
I mean, if we were pissed off or overjoyed.
我是说
I mean--
他只是不想让他的家庭
Yeah, he just didn't want his family...
争吵  我
to bicker. I--
-抱歉  -不
- Sorry. - No.
过来
Come on.
霍克
Hawk...
我们来做一点他喜欢的事情
let's go do something he would've loved.
-求你了  -去你的
- Please. - Fuck you.
来吧
Come on.
我来开车
I'm driving.
我们不是取消去法国
We're not canceling France.
我们只是推迟了它  好吗
We're merely postponing it, okay?
好的  但是我们很接近了
Okay, but we're so close.
一切最后都会发生的
It's all finally happening.
-第三街角  -我们会到那里的
- The third corner-- - And we'll get there.
-我保证  -好的
- I promise. - Okay.
-好的  这会发生的  -已经发生了好吗
- Okay, it will happen. - It is happening, okay?
但是埃迪的爸爸刚死
But Eddie's father just died.
我以为是他前妻的父亲
I thought it was his ex-wife's father.
他们很亲近
They were close.
埃迪和他的前妻
Eddie and his ex?
亲爱的  我说对了  不是吗
Sweetheart? I'm right, aren't I?
你爱上的人喜欢别人
You've fallen for someone who loves someone else.
如果能安慰到你的话
Um, if it's any consolation,
你死时我什么事情都不会推迟
I won't postpone a thing when you die.
事实上  你还没凉我就会去跳舞
In fact, I'll go out dancing while your body's still warm.
你很少能让我想起
There are rare moments that you remind me
你的父亲
of your father.
就像  史蒂夫可以
Like, Steve was capable of such...
那么残酷
quicksilver cruelty.
-你爱上了他  -就像个傻瓜一样
- That you fell for him. - Like a fool.
但这不只是我犯过最大的错  这也是我最开心的事
But out of my greatest mistake, my greatest joy.
而我只是不想看你伤心
And I just don't want to see your heart broken.
是啊  埃迪不是史蒂夫  我也不是你
Yeah. Eddie is not Steve, and I am not you.
-我知道  -不  我爱他
- I understand that. - No, I love him.
这有关系吗
Does it matter?
我  我的幸福  它
D-does my--does my happiness--does it...
如果  如果预言未能实现
If the--f the prophecy were unfulfilled
世  世界没有被清洗
and--and the world wasn't cleansed
但我很开心
but I was happy...
这样对你来说足够吗
Would that be enough for you?
够了
Yes.
但事情不会这样结束
But that's not how things will end.
我只想道个歉  好吗
Hey. I wanted to just apologize, okay,
今晚
about tonight.
我让事情超出控制了
Yeah, I let things just get out of hand and--
我见了一个人
I've been seeing someone.
我
I was...
父亲死时我和他在一起
with him when my father, um...
萨拉  这  这没关系
Sarah, that's--that's okay.
他是名宗教学教授
He's a professor of religion.
他一直在帮我探索我们信仰中的不协调因素
He's been helping me explore incongruities in our faith.
等等  他一直在帮你解决你的问题吗
Wait, he's been helping you question?
-有多久了  -两个月
- For how long? - Two months.
-是什么样的不协调  -这不重要
- What kind of incongruities? - They don't matter.
这就是我不告诉你的原因
That's not why I'm telling you this.
-好吧  -我告诉你
- Okay. - I'm telling you this
是因为我做了很多挖掘和颠覆
because I've been doing a lot of digging and upending and--
而现在我父亲死了  我不知道
And now my father is dead, and I don't know
这些是否是真实的
if any of this is real.
我甚至不知道伊甸园是否是真的
I don't even know if The Garden is real.
是真的吗  埃迪
Is it, Eddie?
还是我父亲只是一些  一些灰烬
Or is my dad just some--some ash?
他一定为我感到非常羞愧
He would be so fucking ashamed of me.
不  萨拉
No, Sarah. Hey.
不不不不  他为你感到骄傲
No, no, no, no, no. He's proud of you.
他非常爱你
He loves you so much.
听着  当我有疑虑时  汉克就不爱我了吗
Look, when I had doubts, did Hank ever stop loving me?
不  正因为我迷失过
No. And it was only because I was lost
我才能找到我回家的路
that I was able to find my way back home.
你也会的
And you will, too.
帖木儿可能给我们的是假地址
Timur may have given us a fake address.
留在车里
Stay in the car.
收到
Roger that.
哈罗德  哈罗德
Harold. Harold.
哈罗德  我让你等在车里
Harold, I told you to wait in the car.
-我认识这个人  -好的  哈罗德
- Hey, I know this guy. - All right, Harold.
-真是个混蛋  -哈罗德  哈罗德
- Total asshole! - Harold, Harold.
哈罗德  哈罗德  过来
Harold! Harold, come on.
过来
Come on.
等等  不不  哈罗德  不
Wait, no, no, Harold. Oh, no!
好  好
Okay, okay.
好的
Okay.
我报警了
I've got an alarm.
警察马上过来
The police will be here any second.
好的  好的
Okay. Yeah, okay.
哈罗德
Harold.
-天啊  -这是我的戒指
- Holy shit. - These are my rings!
-我知道  -是你从我这儿偷走的
‐ I know they are. ‐ No, you stole them from me!
别这样  哈罗德  哈罗德
No, Harold, Harold,
他不知道戒指是偷来的  对不对
he didn't know the rings were stolen, right?
显然你都还不知道
Obviously, you didn't know
自己偷了纪念品  是吧
that you had stolen memorabilia, right?
如果是你偷的  你就不会报警了
If you did, uh, the‐‐ the police wouldn't be on their way.
好吧  我提一个交换条件
Okay. So I propose a deal.
你把戒指给哈罗德
You will give Harold the rings.
-你说什么  -作为交换
‐ Excuse me? ‐ And in exchange‐‐
作为交换
in exchange,
他带你去看一场比赛  可以吗
he's gonna take you to a game, right?
卡尔  我可没有答应过
Cal, we never talked about that.
别这样  你可以把戒指带走
No, you're walking out of here with those rings.
然后你带他去看场比赛
And then you're gonna take this guy to a game,
因为他很崇拜你  好吗
because he worships you, right?
因为这是他应得的
Because he should.
因为你是该死的哈罗德·莱纳斯
Yeah, because you're Harold fucking Linus,
两届世界冠军  好吗
two‐time world champion, right?
有了这个戒指就可以为你证明
And you'll have the rings to prove it.
我还想吃晚饭
I want dinner, too!
比赛之后  我们去吃牛排
After the game, we get a steak dinner.
你他妈真是得寸进尺
You're fucking pushing it.
成交
Deal.
很好
Okay.
很好  跟你合作非常愉快
All right. Nice doing business with you.
你一定会变卦的  对吧
You're not gonna go back on your word, are you?
就像你之前违约一样
Like you did with your contract?
别这样  求你了  求你了
No, come on, come on. Come on, come on, come on.
-你刚刚说什么  -哈罗德
‐ What did you just say? ‐ Harold.
很明显七百万远远不够
Apparently $7 million wasn't enough.
哈罗德  哈罗德  哈罗德
Harold, Harold, Harold, Harold, Harold!
我外公以前老带我来这里
My grandfather used to take me out here.
他会指给我看每一个星座
He'd point out all the constellations.
每一颗星星
Every single one of them.
有一个晚上  他
And this one night, he‐‐
他突然哭了起来
he just started crying.
而且根本停不下来
And he couldn't stop.
我问他
I asked him...
为什么哭
why he was crying.
他看着天空然后
He just looked up and...
说
said...
"你敢相信还有比这更美的
"Can you believe there's a Garden
伊甸园吗"
more beautiful than this?"
-你是  -你就是教授
‐ Yeah? ‐ You the professor?
有什么事吗
I'm sorry?
我想跟你谈谈萨拉·莱恩
I want to talk to you about Sarah Lane.
好吧
Okay.
她说她现在对自己的信仰
She told me that she was exploring incongruities
很不坚定
in her faith.
希望你能跟我说明一下
I was hoping that you could illuminate.
那可能得花很长的时间
Ah, well, that didn't take very long, did it?
-你说什么  -真的
‐ Excuse me? ‐ Yeah.
你是领袖吗  还是什么
You're, what, the leader or something?
你是要我停止用谎言欺骗她吗
You here to tell me to stop filling her head with lies?
说实话  这话从你口中说出来
'Cause let's‐‐to be honest, it's pretty ironic
挺讽刺的  不是吗
coming from someone like you, isn't it?
你他妈有什么毛病
What the fuck is your problem?
把你的手给老子拿开
Get your fucking hands off of me.
-萨拉的父亲去世了  -什么
‐ Sarah just lost her father. ‐ What?
而现在你又夺走了她的信仰
And now you're tearing apart her faith?
对不起  我不知道她父亲去世了
Okay, I'm sorry. I didn't know that about her father.
我不知道她父亲出事了
I didn't know that about her father.
很遗憾听到这个消息  冷静  冷静
I'm very sorry to hear it. Calm down, calm down.
非常遗憾
I'm very sorry to hear that.
是萨拉自己来找我的
Listen, Sarah came to me.
没错
Yeah.
但你却毁了她
And you destroyed her.
你他妈离我老婆远一点
Stay the fuck away from my wife.
总有一些东西在我脑海中挥之不去
See, there's something I can't seem to shake.
如果史蒂文根本就没有爬上阶梯
If Steve never climbed the Ladder
根本没有得到帮助
and received the rungs,
如果这些都是别人帮他一起
if this is just some story
编的故事
that someone helped him write,
那就根本没有伊甸园
then there is no Garden.
你相信吗
Do you believe that?
萨拉  你父亲
Sarah, your father...
的生命将以各种方式延续下去
he lives on in so many ways.
他的生命会在他的孩子身上延续
He lives on in his children,
在他的孙子身上延续
in his grandchildren,
在他拯救的那些生命上延续
in the lives that he changed.
他  萨拉  他与你同在
He‐‐ Sarah, he literally lives in you.
-谢谢你的花  -萨拉
‐ Thank you for the flowers. ‐ Sarah.
葬礼在今天下午
The burial's later this afternoon.
我还有一些事没做完
There's some things I should do.
我可以为你做些什么吗
Is there anything I can do?
我会告诉你的
I'll let you know.
好的
Okay.
昨天晚上你们领袖去了我家
Listen, your leader came to my house last night.
你没跟我说过他是你老公
You didn't tell me that he was your husband.
我们分开了
We're separated.
注意安全  好吗
Okay, well, just be careful there, okay?
-因为他完全  -埃迪是个好人
- 'Cause he's clearly‐‐ ‐ Eddie's a good man.
我会想着你的  萨拉
I'll be thinking of you, Sarah.
再见
Bye.
能耽误你几分钟吗
You have a second?
我刚刚
I just, uh,
把一个人丢在
left a man outside an emergency room
里奇伍德的急诊室门口了
in Ridgewood, uh‐‐
-你把他扔下了  -他应该醒过来了
‐ You left him? ‐ Assuming he survives,
他会认出我的
he'll, uh, likely identify myself
而且会把我当做嫌疑人
and an associate of mine as the suspects.
你告诉我这个是想...
And you're telling me this because...?
我想要你帮我解决这个问题
I want you to make this problem go away.
我为什么要帮你
Why should I help you?
如果我被抓进去了
Well, if I go to prison,
会对我们的运动造成不好的影响  所以...
The Movement would look bad, so...
你因为想曝光运动的创始人是个恋童癖而被威胁
You've been threatening to expose The Movement's founder
却不想对我们造成不好的影响
as a pedophile, but you don't want us to look bad.
这里是我的家
This is my home.
对不起  卡尔  你得自己处理
I'm sorry, Cal, but you're on your own.
我还有一些葬礼前的事务要处理
Now, if you'll please excuse me,
希望你能离开一下
I have things to take care of before the burial.
葬礼
Burial?
你没听说吗
You haven't heard?
汉克·阿姆斯特朗因为心脏病去世了
Hank Armstrong died of a heart attack.
好吧  我的那些废话
Yeah. My nonsense is the last thing
大家都不用理了
our community needs right now.
卡尔
Cal.
如果这次我帮你解决了
If I help you out of this problem...
你得把史蒂文·迈耶的一切信息
you have to hand over everything you have
都告诉我
on Steven Meyer.
好吧
Yeah.
那个人对你做的一切
You know, what that man‐‐  what he did to you...
我感到很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我不明白为什么有人能有汉克这样的父亲
I don't know why some of us get fathers like Hank
而有人却落入
and some of us get
史蒂文这样的畜生手中
monsters like Steve.
我人生的很长一段时间
Yeah, well, most of my life I didn't realize
甚至不到他的可恶
that's what he was, you know?
他说我是他的开心果
Told me I was his greatest joy.
三个多少钱
How much for three?
二十美元
20.
比我印象中的便宜
Cheaper than I remember.
如果你想要质量更好的也可以
You want higher quality, you can pay for it.
我不需要
I don't need higher quality.
你好
Hey, you.
你好  爸爸
Hey, Dad.
我的钱呢
Where's my money?
都没了
All gone.
都被我花光了
I spent it all.
你怎么知道我在哪的
Hey, how'd you know where I was?
起初  我也不知道的
At first, I didn't, and, um...
后来我记起来...
Well, then I remembered...
有天晚上  我给了你两百美元
that one night when I made you $200.
钱多到你有点不知所措
More money than you knew what to do with.
你给我了二十
You gave me 20.
然后你拿着剩下的钱去了大西洋赌城
And then you took the rest to Atlantic City.
玩到一分不剩
Put it all on red.
是啊
That's right.
然后你回家...
Then you came home...
你说  "我想要回那二十美元乖女儿"
And you said, "I'm gonna need that 20 back, baby girl."
接着你就来了这里
And then you came here.
不不
No, no, no, no.
这只是让你飘飘欲仙
Just gonna top you off.
还记得我以前怎么让你嗨的吗
Remember how I used to top you off?
我...
I...
记得
remember.
我跟他说我是你姐
I told him I was your sister.
我发现他分不清
Figured he couldn't tell the difference
印度人和巴基斯坦人
between an Indian and a Pakistani.
你是谁
Who are you?
哈罗德·莱纳斯的同事
An associate of Harold Linus.
他狗娘的要坐牢
Motherfucker can rot in jail.
他还有他那群朋友都是
Him and his friend both.
是  没错
Mm, yes, yes.
这是其中一种解决办法
That's‐‐that's one way this could play out.
你知道那个卖你戒指的
Do you know that young Russian gentleman
俄罗斯年轻小伙吗
you bought the rings from?
你觉得当他知道你压榨他
How do you think he'll respond
会有怎样的反应呢
when he finds out that you dimed on him?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你告发哈罗德
You turn Harold in,
我会匿名给警方打电话
I'll place an anonymous phone call to the police.
他们会突击搜查那年轻小伙的公寓
They'll raid the young man's apartment,
然后他就要坐牢
and, well, he'll go to jail
坐很长  很长时间
for a very, very long time,
而我会让他知道
and I'll make sure that he finds out
是你置他于此地
that it was you who put him there.
跟我说说  你觉得他在杀死你之前
Tell me, do you think he'll make you suffer
会让你好过吗
before he has you killed?
我这里还有另一条路可选
Here's another way this can go.
我叫警察进来  你告诉他
I'll bring in the officer, and you tell him
你不知道是谁袭击你
that you have no idea who jumped you,
等你康复了  哈罗德会带上你
and when you heal, Harold will take you to that game
因为哈罗德·莱纳斯很信守承诺
because Harold Linus is a man of his word.
叫警员进来
Bring the officer in.
不错
Good choice.
你真是个废物  臭女人  你是个败类
You're garbage, lady. You're a garbage human being.
-你还有脸  -不  我知道自己很可悲
- Coming from you... - No, I know I'm pathetic.
我只是孤独而已
But I'm just lonely.
而你是绝对有问题
There's actually something wrong with you.
我不懂
I don't understand.
他把这个当礼物送我
He gave it to me as a gift.
我只是...
I just, um...
想着经历了这些事  你肯定想我走
assumed after everything, you'd want me gone.
等一下  这
Wait, is that‐‐
这就是你拿走戒指的原因吗
Is this why you took the rings?
你想有份保障以防我离开你吗
You wanted an insurance policy in case I left you?
我觉得我不再有用的时候
I figured after I stopped being useful,
你会跟我一拍两散
you'd be done with me.
听着...
Look, um...
你...你对我而言不是有用的货品
You...you're not a commodity to me.
我需要你  玛丽
and I need you, Mary,
并不是因为你有利用价值
not because you're useful.
只是因为我需要你在身边
you know, 'cause I need you.
-对不起  -没事  没事
- I'm sorry. - It's okay. It's okay.
-我很...
- I'm so...
我只是想让你舒服舒服
I just...I want to make you feel good.
别  好了  我意思是你想怎么样
No. Well‐‐well, I mean, what do you want?
-什么意思  -你想要怎么样
- What do you mean? - I mean what do you want.
比如说
Like, um...
比如说你喜欢怎样的抚摸
Like how do you want to be touched?
啊抱歉
No, I'm sorry.
-听着都觉得笨死了  -不会
- It sounds stupid. - No, um...
不会  就是
no, it just...
从没有人这样问过我
No one's ever asked me.
我也需要你
I need you, too.
你昨晚消失了
You disappeared last night.
你去哪了
Where'd you go?
我想静静
Just wanted to be alone for a while.
我知道你跟凯莱布的事了
I know about you and Caleb.
所以是怎么  你现在是同性恋吗
So, what, you're gay now?
我现在不想谈这个
We are not talking about this right now.
很欣慰今天在这里看到那么多熟悉的面孔
It's so good to see so many familiar faces here today
一起送走这位伟大的人
as we honor one of the best men that we've ever known.
我想在座大部分人都还记得
You know, I'm sure most of us remember the moment that...
我们与汉克相遇的时刻
we met Hank.
大家都看到了  我有点...紧张
See, I was...I was nervous.
当然  大家都有点紧张
You know, and, of course, everyone gets a little nervous
当他们第一次
when they're about to
去见女朋友的爸爸的时候
meet their girlfriend's father for the first time.
而我  更是惨不忍睹了
But for me, it was a hundred times worse...
因为我很清楚  毫无疑问
Because I knew, without a shadow of a doubt,
萨拉就是我的唯一
that Sarah was the one.
但汉克  他...他对我很好
But Hank, he was‐‐ he was so kind to me.
我还记得他把手放在我的胸前
You know, I remember him putting his hand on my chest,
然后跟我说
and he told me...
"我能"
"I can s"
"我能感受到你的善心"
"I can see your heart is good."
看  汉克  他信任我
You see, Hank... he believed in me
从最开始就信任我
from the very beginning.
我们尊敬他  以他为榜样
And we honor him by honoring his example.
光明
You see, The Light...
它选择了我
it chose me.
对于那些不听从我决定
And for those who disobey my word
背叛光明的人
turn their backs on The Light.
但那些决定追随我的人  像汉克...
But all who decide to follow me...like Hank...
会在庄园找到自己的一席之地
will find their place in the Garden.
*你带着我*
*You carried me*
*穿越烈火*
*Through the fire*
*谨遵真相*
*In the truth*
*走向光明*
*To The Light*
*你将带领我走向光明*
*You will carry me to The Light*
*你会带领我*
*You will carry me*
*走向光明*
*To The Light*
*我们如同骨头般坚韧*
*We're only as strong as the bonds that hold us*
*手相牵*
*Hand in hand*
*无论沧海桑田*
*Whatever the future brings*
*我与你携手*
*I'll carry you*
*你我手相牵*
*You carry me*
*我与你携手*
*I'll carry you*
*你我手相牵*
*You carry me*
*我们共同携手*
*We will carry each other*
*走向光明  啊光明*
*To The Light, oh, Light*
*我们共同携手*
*We will carry each other*
*我们共同携手走向光明*
*We will carry each other to The Light*
*啊光明*
*Oh, Light*
*共同携手走向光明*
*Carry each other to The Light*
*我与你携手*
*I'll carry you*
*你我手相牵*
*You carry me*
*我与你携手*
*I'll carry you*
*你我手相牵*
*You carry me*
*我们共同携手*
*We will carry each other*
*走向光明  啊光明*
*To The Light, oh, Light*
*共同携手走向光明*
*Carry each other to The Light*
我要相信
I need to believe
你今天所说的一切都是真的
that everything that you said today is true.
我要知道我父亲在庄园里
And I need to know that my father's in The Garden.
我要你帮我把信念找回来
I need you to give me back my faith.